

#### COMPUTER SCIENCE PHD STUDENT

□ (+41) 078-948-15-35 | ■ ognjen.glamocanin@epfl.ch | 回 OgacNS94 | 回 ognjen-glamocanin

## Research Interests

I am a PhD student in Computer Science at EPFL, and my research interests include FPGAs (security, cloud integration, Al acceleration), hardware security, and machine learning applications. My current research focuses on cloud FPGA security and analyzing vulnerabilities introduced by multiple users sharing the same FPGA.

## **Education**

## EPFL, Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne

Lausanne, Switzerland

PhD in Computer Science

Expected grad: August 2023

- · Power side-channel security of shared FPGAs in the cloud
- Thesis advisors: Dr. Mirjana Stojilović and Prof. Babak Falsafi

Sorbonne Université, Paris VI

Paris, France

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2017 - 2018

**University of Novi Sad, Faculty of Technical Sciences** 

Novi Sad. Serbia

B.S. WITH HONOURS IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

2013 - 2017

# Work Experience\_

ARM Sophia Antipolis, France

CPU MICROARCHITECTURE AND DESIGN INTERN

Mar 2018 - Aug 2018

- · Analyzed CPU microarchitectural events for the purposes of power consumption estimation during cycle accurate simulation
- Used ML techniques to model correlation between events and simulated layout-level power consumption
- Enabled power estimation in early microarchitecture design stages by integrating power prediction in a cycle-accurate simulator

FROBAS D.O.O. Novi Sad, Serbia

MACHINE LEARNING HARDWARE ACCELERATION INTERN

Nov 2016 – Jun 2017

• Design and verification of an ML hardware accelerator for multi-layer perceptron (MLP) artificial neural networks (ANNs)

ELSYS EASTERN EUROPE

Belgrade, Serbia

HARDWARE FUNCTIONAL VERIFICATION INTERN

Jul 2016 - Oct 2016

• Used SystemVerilog and the UVM methodology to build a functional verification environment for an OCP2UART bridge

### **Publications**

#### RDS: FPGA Routing Delay Sensors for Effective Remote Power Analysis Attacks

**TCHES** 

(conditionally accepted)

DAVID SPIELMANN\*, O. GLAMOČANIN\*, M. STOJILOVIĆ (\* EQUAL CONTRIBUTION)

2023

- · Novel FPGA-based voltage sensor architecture using routing resources.
- · Evaluation showing superior sensing capabilities than the state of the art, even on datacenter accelerator cards (Alveo U200).

## Temperature Impact on Remote Power Side-Channel Attacks on Shared FPGAs

DATE

O. GLAMOČANIN, H. BAZAZ, M. PAYER, M. STOJILOVIĆ

2023

- Analysis of temperature impact on FPGA-voltage sensors and remote power-analysis attacks.
- Impact of temperature effects on ML-based power side-channel attacks.

## The Side-Channel Metrics Cheat Sheet

CSUR

 $K.\ Papagiannopoulos^*, \textbf{O.\ Glamočanin}^*, M.\ Azouaoui^*, D.\ Ros^*, F.\ Regazzoni^*, M.\ Stojilović^* \ (*\ equal\ contribution)$ 

2022

- Analysis and comparison of methods for power side-channel security evaluation, with extensive experimental examples.
- Work accompanied with an open-source library of metrics for side-channel analysis.

## Improving First-Order Threshold Implementations of SKINNY

INDOCRYPT

A. Caforio, D. Collins, **O. Glamočanin**, and S. Banik

2021

- An efficient threshold implementation protection against power side-channel attacks for the SKINNY cipher.
- Experimental evaluation showing no existence of first-order power side-channel leakage.

#### Shared FPGAs and the Holy Grail: Protections Against Side-Channel and Fault Attacks

O. GLAMOČANIN. D. G. MAHMOUD, F. REGAZZONI, AND M. STOJIJ OVIĆ

**DATE** 2021

- Analysis of recently proposed methods for protection against side-channel and fault attacks in shared FPGAs.
- · Insights on the versatility and inter-operability of the countermeasures, with an emphasis on future research directions.

#### Are Cloud FPGAs Really Vulnerable to Power-Analysis Attacks?

DATE 2020

O. GLAMOČANIN, L. COULON, F. REGAZZONI, AND M. STOJILOVIĆ

- Implementation of an FPGA-based voltage sensor on the state-of-the-art cloud FPGAs: Xilinx UltraScale+ on AWS F1 instances.
- Demonstration that remote power side-channel attacks are possible on cloud-scale FPGAs, and pose a serious threat to FPGA multitenancy.

#### **Built-In Self-Evaluation of First-Order Power Side-Channel Leakage for FPGAs**

.\_\_\_\_

O. GLAMOČANIN, L. COULON, F. REGAZZONI, AND M. STOJILOVIĆ

2020

- Demonstration that FPGA-based voltage sensors can be used for remote power side-channel leakage estimation.
- Design of a first remote power side-channel leakage assessment system, allowing side-channel security reevaluation on deployed devices.

## **Honors & Awards**

2016

2018 EPFL EDIC Fellowship.

Switzerland

Fellowship for first-year PhD students

2017 French Government Scholarship for International Students,

France

Full scholarship for master studies in France

Dr Vladan Desnica Award,

Serbia

Best student of the microcomputer electronics track

# Teaching Experience \_\_

**EPFL**Lausanne, Switzerland

TEACHING ASSISTANT Feb 2019 – ongoing

- Computer Architecture: Head TA, managing the course and lab sessions in CPU micro-architecture for 2<sup>nd</sup> year B.S. students
- **System Programming Project**: Leading lab sessions in C for 2<sup>nd</sup> year B.S. students
- Information, Computation, Communication: Head TA, managing the course and leading lab sessions in Python and C for 1st year B.S. students

University of Novi Sad Novi Sad, Serbia

TEACHING ASSISTANT Sep 2016 – Jun 2017

- Electrical Circuit Theory: Leading computer lab sessions in MATLAB for 2<sup>nd</sup> year B.S. students
- Systems and Signals: Leading computer lab sessions in MATLAB for 2<sup>nd</sup> year B.S. students

## Technical Skills

**Programming languages:** C/C++ (10yrs), Python (6yrs), SystemVerilog, MATLAB

**Scripting languages:** Python, Bash, TCL

Hardware description languages: VHDL (9yrs), Verilog, SystemC

CAD EDA tools: Xilinx ISE, Xilinx Vivado and Vitis, Cadence NCSim

# Languages

**FESTIVAL COORDINATOR** 

Serbian: Mother tongue
English: fluent (level C2)
French: fluent (level C1)
German: beginner (level A1)

## **Extracurricular Activities**

## The Illuminations of Jules Verne

Novi Sad, Serbia

2012 - 2015

• Head coordinator of the music part of the festival of light, music and lanterns *The Illuminations of Jules Verne* 

- Created and coordinated the music program, logistics
- https://www.facebook.com/ZilvernovskeIluminacije/

December 20, 2022 Ognjen Glamočanin · Résumé